<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Price Discovery on Democratize Data For Insights</title>
    <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/price-discovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Price Discovery on Democratize Data For Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/price-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When Earnings Announcements Go After 4 PM</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/after-hour-trading-and-information-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/after-hour-trading-and-information-processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the market during trading hours, the after-hours market is characterized by an illiquid trading environment, high trading costs, a high degree of information asymmetry, low trading volume, and most importantly, relatively &amp;lsquo;inactive&amp;rsquo; market participants (Barclay and Hendershott, 2004 JF), all making it challenging to trace information incorporation and price discovery in the after-hours market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, to avoid the excess volatility during the trading hours and allow more time for investors to acquire and integrate the information into their valuation assessments, firms and regulators have become more prone to release material news outside trading hours in recent years. Take the firms&amp;rsquo; earnings announcements as an example. Figure 1 from Chan and Marsh (2024, WP) plots the intraday distribution of earnings announcement frequencies in recent years. In contrast to the situation decades ago, when over 80% of earnings announcements were released during trading hours (Patell and Wolfson, 1982 TAR), after-hour earnings announcements have become dominant nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
