<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Media on Democratize Data For Insights</title>
    <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Media on Democratize Data For Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Twitter API: Door To Social Media Analysis I</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/door-to-twitter-analysis-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/door-to-twitter-analysis-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last few decades, a series of papers published in top accounting journals have repeatedly proved that &lt;strong&gt;Twitter data could empower very fascinating research ideas&lt;/strong&gt;. To give readers an &lt;strong&gt;intuition about the potential of Twitter data&lt;/strong&gt;, I would roughly show three directions and their relative examples which I have deepest impression through my limited personal reading experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wisdom of crowds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bartov, Faurel, and Mohanram (2018, TAR) found opinions of individuals tweeted just prior to a firm’s earnings announcement can predict its earnings and announcement returns. Similarly, Tang (2018, JAR) showed the customer responses towards a firm&amp;rsquo;s products in Twitter obtain a siginificant predictive power for the upcoming firm sales.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter API: Door To Social Media Analysis II</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/door-to-twitter-analysis-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/door-to-twitter-analysis-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the background information about Twitter API v2 in my last blogpost &lt;a href=&#34;https://mengjiexu.com/post/door-to-twitter-analysis-i/&#34;&gt;Twitter API: Door To Social Media Analysis I&lt;/a&gt;. In this blogpost, I will replicate the Tweets extraction porcess of Bartov, Faurel, and Mohanram (2018, TAR), which found that opinions of individuals tweeted just prior to a firm’s earnings announcement can predict its earnings and announcement returns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From a perspective of implementation, we need to get all the tweets which mentioned a given firm in a specified time range. Consistent to the paper&amp;rsquo;s definition, the targeted tweets should:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
