<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VAR on Democratize Data For Insights</title>
    <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/var/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VAR on Democratize Data For Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://xumj2021.github.io/tags/var/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dig into Estimation of VAR Coefficients, IRFs, and Variance Decomposition in Stata</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/manually-replicate-statas-practice-in-estimations-of-var-irfs-and-variance-decomposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/manually-replicate-statas-practice-in-estimations-of-var-irfs-and-variance-decomposition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While people can always use integrated commands in Stata (e.g., &lt;code&gt;var&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;svar&lt;/code&gt;) to produce abundant outputs of VAR estimation, many can not confidently interpret these results without knowing how they are theoretically defined and practically calculated. Manually replicating the outputs of the Stata&amp;rsquo;s integrated commands for VAR estimation will be very helpful to resolve this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I will firstly provide the theoretical calculation formulas of reduced-form coefficients, IRFs, Structural IRFs, Orthogonalized IRFs, and Forecast Error Variance Decomposition. Then I will follow their theoretical definition to manually calculate these outputs in Stata. Finally, I will compare the manually computed results with the outputs generated from Stata&amp;rsquo;s integrated commands (see in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mengjiexu.com/post/common-practice-of-var-estimation-in-stata/&#34;&gt;the last blog&lt;/a&gt;) and cross-check the validity of my manual computation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimations of VAR, IRFs, and Variance Decomposition in Stata</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/common-practice-of-var-estimation-in-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/common-practice-of-var-estimation-in-stata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is the second one of my 3 blogs about VAR model. In this blog, I will introduce how to use Stata&amp;rsquo;s integrated commands &lt;code&gt;var&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;svar&lt;/code&gt; to estimate the VAR model, which is also the common practices for researchers in VAR estimation. While it has little incremental value to an extant blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.stata.com/2016/08/09/vector-autoregressions-in-stata/&#34;&gt;Vector autoregressions in Stata written by David Schenck&lt;/a&gt;, this blog will serve as an important benchmark for my manual calculations of all the major VAR estimation outputs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mengjiexu.com/post/manually-replicate-statas-practice-in-estimations-of-var-irfs-and-variance-decomposition/&#34;&gt;the next blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touch into the Vector Auto Regression Model</title>
      <link>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/touch-into-var/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xumj2021.github.io/post/touch-into-var/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://mengjiexu.com/post/an-information-based-decomposition-of-stock-price/&#34;&gt;my last blog&lt;/a&gt;, I recognized the potential of the information-based variance decomposition method introduced by Brogaard et al. (2022, RFS) and showed interests of applying this method into my own research.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As replicating Brogaard et al. (2022, RFS) requires some manipulations on the VAR estimation outputs, I took some time to figure out the theory and estimation of the reduced-form VAR coefficients, Impulse response functions (IRFs), structural IRFS, orthogonalized IRFs, and variance decomposition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
